ERAY FIRAT

Personal Details

Birth Year : 1983 **E-mail :** erayfirat.ef@gmail.com

Marital Status : Married Profession : Web Developer

Phone: +90 530 458 4624

Profile

Since 2013, I have developed web applications using Microsoft architectures in different business environments. I have worked at corporate level in environments that require teamwork. I tried to write applications as error-free as possible, to meet the needs in the long term and in a flexible way. I used Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code as application development environment and TFS (Team Foundation Server) for version control tool and task/process tracking. Although I mostly like to develop on the backend side, I generally worked as FullStack Developer. However, I worked as a CCNA and CCNA Security (Network and Network Security) instructor for active Cisco products for 3 years. At the end of this process, I became a CCNP instructor. I worked on corporate and individual Cyber Security issues with Network Security and got CCNA CyberOps certification. With Cyber Security, I worked individually on Linux, IOT, IOT Security, Big Data, Al and Python programming language.

Education

Çankaya University	Computer Engineering	02/2021 - Present
(Ankara)	(Master's Degree-Full Scholarship)	
Hacettepe University	Computer Engineering	09/2012 - 08/2013
(Ankara)	(IT Certification)	
Military Academy	Systems Engineering	09/2002 - 08/2006
(Ankara)	(Bachelor's Degree)	

Employment

Agartha Technology Web Application Developer 02/2020 – 07/2021

(Ankara) (Enterprise Resource Planning)

Work as a member of a team that develops Entity Resources Planning (ERP) Project for a government agecy. We use LLBLGen for ORM tool and use Telerik Kendo-UI for frontend development. Project architecture is MVC. Besides Telerik Reporting Service and MSSQL/PostgreSQL are used for this project.

Government Instructor 11/2016 – 01/2020

(Ankara) (Network and Network Security)

Teach graduate students network security. We use Cisco Network Academy environment (CCNA / CCNA Security).

Government Web Application Developer 06/2013 – 10/2016

(Ankara) (Human Resources Management Systems)

Work as a web developer in a team of Human Resources Management Systems. Daily job is develop, test and maintain. We migrated project from .NET Framework to Entity Framework. I migrated a desktop project(written in Delphi) to the web project. We mostly use Visual Basic, C#, LINQ, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MSSQL, SSRS, TFS.

Key Skills

Backend

- Asp.Net
- MVC
- Web Forms
- C#
- SQL
- Entity Framework
- Linq

- OOP
- SSRS (SQL Server Reporting Services)
- Team Foundation Servers
- Visual Studio
- LLBLGen (ORM)
- Python
- GIT

Frontend

- HTML 5
- CSS
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Jquery

Network/Cyber Security

- CCNA Instructor
- CCNA Security Instructor
- CCNP Instructor
- CCNA Cyber Ops(Certified)

Languages

Turkish (Fluent)

English (Advanced)